[Music]
do
good morning the days are starting late
over here as we don't have sun until
nine at the earliest
it makes it easy to sleep in or read
spooky wintry stories in the soft light
before the day takes over
[Music]
over a year ago i purchased a
historically inspired gown
i wanted to wear it to a fantasy fair
but didn't get the chance to go
i decided that today in celebration of
the season it would only be apt to put
it on
i appreciate you humoring me as i play
dress-up
[Music]
for some reason it reminds me of clara's
night dress from the nutcracker by
tchaikovsky
i used to dance ballet as a child sadly
i was told i grew too tall to be
accepted in the advanced programs and
that my height would make me look
mismatched from the other dancers
and so my dream to play clara would not
be fulfilled
instead i got to play an evil rat which
was a bit of a blow for a child who
desperately wanted to be a fairy
princess
at the time i felt like a dream of mine
had been shattered not understanding
that the limitations of one dance
academy didn't mean i couldn't continue
to enjoy ballet
[Music]
looking back it seems like such a far
away memory something so small and
insignificant but it was one of many
moments where i felt however briefly
like i didn't measure up and that the
path i intended to take was now veering
away in some unknown direction
this continued to happen as an adult i
interviewed for jobs i wanted and didn't
get them
i submitted my writing and art to
magazines and was rarely if ever
published
over time through a series of failures
and occasional wins i was left
thoroughly confused as to what i was
good at
maybe i wasn't a genius in any specific
field no hidden talent i just had to
find in order to do something amazing
i was not the smartest person i knew nor
the most sociable or popular
i'd been painting my entire life and yet
i had an artist friend who could create
photorealistic drawings within a few
days when i would just turn up some
rushed bunny sketches
[Music]
maybe i began to think i was just an
average person it made sense it wouldn't
be a term unless many of us are
and it's funny because it was only by
accepting that possibility that i found
my path
i stopped trying to be the best it was
liberating because the journey became
about doing what i could with what i had
for example the best art was what
brought me joy to create even if a bunny
fairy will not hang in a prestigious
gallery anytime soon
and i don't mean this to start a debate
over whether or not you or i are average
because all of this is relative
intelligence and talent is often
misunderstood and i know that now
you could have all the book knowledge of
the world be a business tycoon solve the
mysteries of the planet
but if you can't figure out how to be
happy or love unconditionally then
aren't you missing something worth
knowing
doesn't your intelligence fail you at a
crucial point
[Music]
okay
i'm gonna
[Music]
my search for meeting involved keeping
true to the mysterious winding road
ahead shrouded and missed
eventually it brought me here to my home
to selling my art at farmers markets and
eventually online
i now consider myself both intelligent
and talented in my own paula way
i am in my own category as are you
it isn't a competition if we choose not
to participate
because winning usually involves other
people measuring your success and
improving that title
why would you ever want to give anyone
else that power over you
i don't know maybe you do i definitely
don't have things figured out
maybe i'm just a rather odd woman
wearing a fancy gown for no particular
reason
making an overly detailed gingerbread
house constructing fairy tales through
the lens of her camera and trying to
live a quiet but meaningful life
and asking some questions along the way
i'm wishing you a wonderful festive
season
and i'm sending you my love
[Music]
hello everyone i am sorry if the audio
is not good
this is a bit of a spur at the moment
but i just wanted to wish you all a
wonderful december
i was looking back at this year and
thinking how amazing it is
when you know life offers opportunities
and you know when you're just trying to
do your best it kind of
unravels in unexpected ways
you know i can think back to so many
moments in my life where i realized my
path had changed course that i could no
longer keep working towards the goal
that i had before
be it as a student or working in a
specific company or just realizing in
one shape or form that i couldn't go
forward anymore i had to carve out a new
path
and that those moments were always so
intimidating and scary and i doubted i
would ever find
my
road i i didn't know if i would ever
find what i wanted to do or what i was
even good at but you know it just ended
up not being so important because
all those
you know
opportunities that fell through
you know all brought me here and all
taught me a lot in the process but it's
funny how
you know things
can work out in time they just don't
always work out the way you wanted them
to
and sometimes that can offer something
even more special i once read a book
about a veterinarian who worked in
yorkshire his name was james harriet
it's a pretty popular set of books and
there was one chapter that stayed true
to me that
he said that he looks back on decisions
he made that he wishes he had made
differently
now that he has
the ability to look into the past and
see how things went
that
there's no point in being upset at
yourself for making mistakes
or not taking certain opportunities
because all you can do is do your very
best at the moment
and make the best decision you can with
a good intention and using the knowledge
and abilities available to you at the
time and it's so much easier to look
back
and
you know as a wiser person and
see that situation differently but at
the time you were just trying to do your
best and
that's all you can hope for
and that you need to be proud of
yourself for that
and so
i'm trying to continue that same
enthusiasm into the new year no matter
what it brings you know i will continue
trying to do my best and trying to learn
and i wish the same for you
there is so many possibilities in the
new year i think anne of green gables
put it really well i'm pretty sure she
said every day is a clean slate i think
with no mistakes in it so
i
am wishing you all a wonderful and
hopeful new year i will see you next
week i'm sending my love i hope this
december
is wonderful for you and that you can
stay safe and healthy
i have my family visiting right now so
it's just a wonderful time
and my sister's visiting from houston
and she has not really experienced that
much snow so it's been very exciting to
spend some time with her and
walk around the town and do a lot of
things with her i've missed her very
much so
anyway
have a wonderful week and i will see you
very soon goodbye